Bengaluru, India keyurkamdar6390@gmail.com

SUMMARY:

I am a seasoned Software Engineer with a wide variety of professional experience in design, implementation and integration. Having a strong communication, leadership and technical background. I am focused and self-motivated with excellent organizational skills. Willing to get involved with new technologies.

EDUCATION:

Master of Science in Computer Science

August 2013 – May 2015

California State University Long Beach, US

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Engineering

August 2007 – May 2012

Dharmsinh Desai University, IN

EMPLOYMENT:

Walmart Global, Bengaluru, IN

Senior Software Engineer

Oct 2021 - Current

Jun 2019 – Sep 2021

Software Engineer - III

- Designing and implementing a highly scalable, real-time in-house Ad-Server for Walmart Global Tech.
- Rewriting the ad decision, ad data ingestion module for the Walmart.com website.
- Lead contributor and maintainers for the Ad-Server ecosystem.
- Developed new modules with java spring boot, kafka, cosmos, aerospike, microservices, REST apis and MySql.
- Contributed in self-serve Ad Management portal for walmart.com and worked closely with Scala, Play and MS SQL.
- Other duties include reviewing code, mentoring associates, writing documentation and training modules.

PRN, San Jose, US

Software Engineer - II

Jun 2017 - Jan 2019

- Designed and implemented a scalable platform for in-store digital Ad-Signage systems.
- Evaluated interface between hardware and software to work with the point-of-sale system with Android apps.
- Helped to build and enhance a highly available, scalable, real-time and secure system used by customers worldwide.
- Collaborated closely with other team members to plan, design and develop robust backend service solutions.
- Developed new modules using core java, event based architecture, AWS and SQL to augment product offering.

xAd Inc, Mountain View, US

Software Engineer

Aug 2015 – May 2017

- Implemented a self-serve campaign management portal for location based ad platform.
- Contributed software engineering expertise in the development of products through software development life cycle from requirement definition through successful deployment.
- Designed and implemented a python based application tool to make automated campaign insertion.
- Stored, retrieved and manipulated data for close analysis of system capabilities.
- Closely worked with Java, hibernate, Python, MySql, REST apis and redis

Advanced E-Media Inc. /WebJaguar, Aliso Viejo, US

Jr. Java Developer (Internship)

Mar 2015 – May 2015

- Executed server side tasks using Servlets and enhancements on change requests for an e-commerce application.
- Implemented data access module in spring with ibatis.

MarkTeQ, Ahmedabad, IN

Software Developer

Jan 2013 – July 2013

- Worked on a project to monitor and manage employee work allocation and progress on a daily basis.
- Developed new modules in agile environment with C# ASP.Net to implement rest services, ADO.Net for db connectivity, stored procedure, functions, triggers with 3-tier architecture in MsSql.

Synoverge Technologies Inc, Ahmedabad, IN

Associate Software Engineer

May 2011 – Dec 2012

- Worked in an integrated software system for a public safety organization named Cyrun.
- Developed features across multiple subsystems, including collaboration in requirements definition, prototyping, design, coding, testing and deployment within scrum development environment.
- Designed large numbers of wpf forms, custom controls using xaml language for dynamic web parts for personalized content which allows change, edit, move the content on pages as per client's requirement.
- Implemented web based data visualization with strong graphical programming to draw a workflow in real environment with c# and xaml silverlight.

SKILL HIGHLIGHTS:

Language

Java, Scala, Python, JavaScript, C#

Database Management

MySql, Aerospike, Redis, Cosmos DB, Postgres, Redshift, Cassandra, MS SQL, Oracle, SQLite

Technologies/Concepts

Kafka, Microservices, Distributed Systems, Akka, REST, gRPC + protobuf, Gradle, Elastic Search, Prometheus, JDBC, Maven, quartz, Celery, Generators, Shell Scripting, TCP/IP Socket Programming

Cloud-Based Technologies

GCP, Docker, AWS

Framework

Spring Boot, Play, Hibernate, Junit, Mockito, Gatling, MVC, Flask, Sanic, jQuery, Brite Snow, Ajax, ASP .Net, Silverlight, WPF

Web/App Server

Apache, Nginx, Jetty, IIS, Tomcat, HAProxy load balancer

Tools/Editor

Git, IntelliJ, Jira, Eclipse, Android SDK, PvCharm, Visual Studio, TFS, Netbeans, Android SDK